about.md 1/28/2023

I am Yuqiang Yang, a master candidate at South China University of Technology, supervised by Prof. Chenguang Yang. Now I am also working as an intern at Application Innovate Laboratory, Huawei Technologies Co.Ltd.

My research interests are robotic learning from demonstration, mobile manipulation and whole-body control. Specifically, I have been exploring and exploiting the potentiality of the wheeled mobile manipulators in acquiring manipulation skills from human demonstration, such as picking-and-placing or openning the door. Recently I am working on the wholebody control of the wheeled mobile maniputors through SLQ-MPC controller implemented in OCS2. This goal of this project is to enable mobile manipulators to plan and execute the manipulation in real time in a cluttered environment.

# Education

## **South China University of Technology**

Master, Robotics Sep. 2022 - Present

School of Automation Science and Engineering

Supervisor: Prof. Chenguang Yang

#### **South China University of Technology**

Bachelor, School of Automation Science and Engineering

Sep. 2018 - Jun. 2022

GPA: 3.94/4.0 (ranked first)

# Research Experiences

#### Realtime wholebody control of the mobile manipulator in cluttered environment

Application Innovate Laboratory, Huawei

2022.10 - present

Advisor: Dr. Chen Chen

- Construct the occupancy grid map and ESDF based on FIESTA. Then bias the sample of RRT\* to get an initial guiding path according to the topological map in Cartesian space.
- Propose and analyse the adaptive MPC theorectically to improve the convergence and optimality in complex environments where multiple non-convex costs or contraints exist
- The proposed framework is verified through experiments about picking and placing a cup gracefully in clutted environment.

# Learning the coordination motion of mobile manipulators through human demonstration

School of Automation Science and Engineering, SCUT

2022.01 - 2022.09

Advisor: Prof. Chenguang Yang

 Propose a whole-body LfD framework through Gaussian Process, which endows the mobile manipulator's skill learning process with features of large-scale convergence, coordination working and disturbance rejection, after just a few human demonstrations. about.md 1/28/2023

• An efficient kinesthetic teaching method is devised based on the weighted least-norm (WLN) inverse kinematics solution and an admittance controller, which facilitates human users to guide the mobile manipulator to perform tasks.

• The framework allows for human-in-the-loop correction when the whole-body is conducting a task.

# **Project Experiences**

## Self-balanced smart car with wireless charging capability

School of Automation Science and Engineering, SCUT

2020.01 - 2020.08

Advisor: Dr. An Chen

- Design and implement the adaptive wireless-charging algorithm to quickly charge the supercapacitors mounted on the car. A series control system from the charing power loop to the charging current loop is designed to stablize the charging power at 30W.
- Control the position and orientation of the two-wheeled car to complete a complex race track with different elements such as circles and slopes. The perception infomation mainly comes from the onboard IMU and electromagnetic sensors.
- We finished the race in fifth national ranking with a time of 23.8s and won the first prize.

### Graceful wholebody pick-and-place for mobile manipulator

Application Innovate Laboratory, Huawei

2022.10 - 2022.11

Advisor: Dr. Chen Chen

- Train GGCNN for the peception of the objects' pose and the grasp quality. The inputs of GGCNN are pointclouds while the ouputs are the grasp quality, width and orientation.
- Jointly consider the manipulability, energy, manipulator orientation, path tracking in the QP solvers. The dynamic-weighted QP is implemented based on the tracking error to acheive graceful picking-and-placing.

## Honor & Awards

National Scholarship	2021-10
Scholarship of Guangzhou Automobile Group Co., Ltd• National Scholarship•	2020-10 2019-10
Meritorious Winner of Interdisciplinary Contest In Modeling (ICM)●	2021-03

# Skills

### **Programming and Learning Framework:**

Python, MATLAB, C/C++, PyTorch, Pybullet

#### **Robotics:**

about.md 1/28/2023

DH, wholebody control, Admittance/Impedance Control, Gravity Compensation, Shared control, teleoperation

# **Hardware Experience:**

Franka, UR10, Mobile Manipulator, Robotiq 2F85, Vicon, Touch X, ATI sensors, STM32